fernanda mora

B.Sc. Applied Mathematics

■ B.Sc. Actuarial Sciences

■ M.Sc. Computer Science candidate



about Mexico city Mobile 5528862399

fernandamoralba@gmail

fernanda-mora.com

github.com/Sophie-Germain

languages

spanish (native) english (high proficiency)

programming

R, Python, Matlab (fair) Java, C, C++ Bash (basic)

other

PostgreSQL, LaTeX, Sublime, Office Suite, GitHub, Docker

about

"If you cannot measure it, you cannot improve it". My major goal is to **generate value** through *state-of-the-art technologies and models* that tackle relevant problems in *society, government and companies*. My second goal is to promote a quantitative & data-driven approach to problem-solving and decision-making.

To achieve this I have developed a **unique academic & industry experience** that combines **theory** + **research** with a **practical** + **client-oriented approach**. Please take a look to my **website** to find a more detailed picture of my profile.

Academic interests

- Computer Science: computer architecture, distributed computing
- Data Science and Machine Learning:
 Big Data, Deep Learning
- Pure Mathematics: Set Theory, Functional Analysis, Group Theory
- Statistics and Finance: Bayesian, Derivatives, Risk Theory

Non-academic interests

- Strategic and Management Consulting
- · Value proposition and pricing
- Business intelligence analytics with data-driven solutions
- Integration, management, securing, and analysis of enterprise and governmental data
- Web development

education

| since 2015 | M.Sc. candidate in Computer Science Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de Mexico Working on machine reading comprehension |
|------------|---|
| 2015 | B.Sc. in Applied Mathematics Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de Mexico |
| | Thesis with special mention: Deep Learning Fundamentals Applied to Electric |
| | Energy Consumption Forecasting in Mexico. Link to thesis Link to deck |
| 2012 | B.Sc. in Actuarial Sciences Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de Mexico |
| | Thesis with special mention. Link to thesis |

academic experience

| 2016, 2m | Carnegie Mellon University Worked with Profr. Eric Nyberg in Machine Learning models for Q&A at the |
|----------|---|
| | Language Technologies Institute. Link to project report |
| 2016 | Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de Mexico Graduate Seminar Professor Teaching Data Mining tools to support decision making. Github repo |
| 2015, 6m | Computational Research and Analysis Laboratory (ITAM) Data Scientist Machine learning and visualization of credit data for nonpayment prediction |
| 2010, 6m | Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de Mexico Economics IV (non-competitive markets) Teaching Assistant |

industry experience

| since 2015 | Freelance consulting (Mexican Secretary of Energy, Abb\ Business strategy, data mining and statistical consulting | /ie) Consultant |
|------------|---|---------------------|
| 2015, 2m | AbbVie Mexico <i>Tailor-made value propositions for AbbVie's drug portfolio</i> | Project Coordinator |
| 2013-2014 | LifeSciences Consultants Management Health economics, cost-effectiveness analysis, market access | gement Consultant |
| 2010-2011 | Sociedad Financiera Campesina Evaluation and assessment of credit portfolios | Financial Analyst |
| 2012, 3m | ADRISA Estimation and forecasting of the premium of life insurances | Actuarial Analyst |
| 2009-2010 | Cuasar Capital S.C. Financial assessment of infrastructure and real-state projects | Financial Analyst |

publications

Local layered algorithmic model for topological design of rural telecommunications networks. Presented on the International Conference on Operations Research for Development, ICORD 2016. Link to paper

Carga Económica de la Diabetes Mellitus en México, 2013. Fundación Mexicana para la Salud A.C. Link to paper

conferences

Dataday Mexico 2017: Speaker with a talk on Deep Learning.

International Conference on Operations Research for Development, ICORD 2016: Presenter of a paper and revisor of two papers.

acknowledgments

- 90% Bachelor's tuition scholarship for strong academic performance
- 60% Master's tuition scholarship for strong academic performance
- National Council of Science and Technology Master's scholarship for strong academic performance